HAZEM ABO-DONIA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING STUDENT

Brooklyn, New York habodoni@stevens.edu

Education

Stevens Institute of Technology

Hoboken, New Jersey

B.E. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

September 2022 - Current

- 3.73 GPA
- Stevens Institute of Technology Grant Recipient
- Edwin A. Stevens Scholarship Recipient

Brooklyn Technical High School

Brooklyn, New York

June 2022

- 4.0 GPA (98.09% Cumulative)
- AP Scholar Award
- Sean Cummings Memorial Award Brooklyn Technical High School Football

Summary

I am currently a freshman at Stevens Institute of Technology. I have experience with both Python and Java, including their implementations in data visualization. I am AutoCAD Certified, ACI (American Concrete Institute) Certified, and CST (Certified Surveying Technician) Certified. Throughout high school I was a part of the Varsity Football Team as well as the Varsity Track and Field team. I am interested in gaining experience in the field of software engineering and development in the New York Metropolitan Area.

Employment

University Settlement Society of New York

Brooklyn, New York

Group Leader

July 2022 - August 2022

• Provided children with the opportunity to sharpen their reading, writing, and mathematics skills over the summer through personalized and enriching lesson plans and activities.

Experience

University of Pennsylvania

Student Programmer

June 2021 - August 2021

- Decreased risk in a stock portfolio through coding a program which clusters various stocks based off market reactions and price movement.
- Utilizes K-Means Clustering (KMC) algorithm, Principal Component Analysis (PCA), and Normalization.

ACE GNY Mentorship Program

Mechanical Engineering Team

October 2020 – June 2021

- Maximized energy efficiency and reduced installation costs of HVAC systems in a commercial building design.
- In charge of HVAC system and installation process selection.

Steme LLC

Student Tutor in Mathematics

June 2020 - May 2022

• Provided volunteer tutoring to middle school and high school students in geometry, algebra, and pre-calculus.

Programs, and Skills

Python, React, C++, Java, TypeScript, JavaScript, Git, Visual Studio Code, Microsoft Excel/Google Sheets, Microsoft Word/Google Docs, Microsoft PowerPoint/Google Slides, Autodesk Inventor, Autodesk AutoCAD, Team Management, Project Scheduling, Problem Solving Ability, Communication, Project Estimation

Certifications

American Concrete Institute (ACI) Certified Concrete Tester (June 2022), Certified Surveying Technician (CST) Certified Surveyor Level 1 (June 2022), Autodesk AutoCAD Certified (January 2022)

Languages

English (Native), Arabic (Advanced), French (Intermediate)